Cowshed, and once on Midsummer Day, the anniversary of the rebellion.
Chapter 5 As winter drew on, Molly became more and more troublesome.
She was late for work every morning and excused herself by saying that she had
overslept, and she complained of mysterious pains, although her appetite was excellent.
On every kind of pretext, she would run away from work and go to the drinking
pool, where she would stand, foolishly gazing at her own reflection in the water.
But there were also rumors of something more serious.
One day, as Molly strolled blithely into the yard, flirting her long tail and
chewing at a stalk of hay, Clover took her aside.
>> Molly, I have something very serious to say to you.
This morning, I saw you looking over the hedge that divides Animal Farm from Foxwood.
One of Mr. Pilkington's men was standing on the other side of the hedge, and I
was a long way away, but I am almost certain I saw this.
He was talking to you, and you were allowing him to stroke your nose.
What does that mean, Molly?
>> He didn't. I wasn't. It isn't true.
>> cried Molly, beginning to prance about and paw the ground.
>> Molly, look me in the face.
Do you give me your word of honor that that man was not stroking your nose?
>> It isn't true.
>> repeated Molly, but she could not look Clover in the face, and the next moment,
she took to her heels and galloped away into the field.
A thought struck Clover.
Without saying anything to the others, she went to Molly's stall and turned
over the straw with her hoof.
Hidden under the straw was a little pile of lump sugar and several bunches of
ribbon of different colors.
Three days later, Molly disappeared.
For some weeks, nothing was known of her whereabouts.
Then, the pigeons reported that they had seen her on the other side of Willingdon.
She was between the shafts of a smart dog cart painted red and black, which
was standing outside a public house.
A fat, red-faced man in check breeches and gaiters, who looked like a publican,
was stroking her nose and feeding her with sugar.
Her coat was newly clipped, and she wore a scarlet ribbon round her forelock.
She appeared to be enjoying herself, so